Guide to the Manuscripts Bound in Printed Books in the Osborn Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Documents
  - Hayward, John, 1905-1965 ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Cheyne Walk, [London], 1950 Jan 31 (Box pe 358)
  - Hayward, John, 1905-1965 ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Cheyne Walk, [London], 1951 Jan 24 (Box pe 358)
    Criticizes work of James Thorpe
    discusses forthcoming exhibition
    "Le livre anglais."
  - Hayward, John, 1905-1965 ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Cheyne Walk, [London], 1951 Jun 9 (Box pe 358)
    Asks for loan of books for "Le livre
    anglais."
  - Hayward, John, 1905-1965 ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Cheyne Walk, [London], 1951 Jun 12 (Box pe 358)
    Lists books he wishes to borrow.
  - Henry, --- ALS to Frank Percy and Joanne Wilson, Venice, Italy, 1956 Jun 18 (Box pe 348.v2)
    1 p.; 10 x 15 cm.
    Greetings from Venice, Italy; reports
    that Vicenze has suffered in war.
  - Hoeniger, F. David ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, London, 1957 May 19 (Box pe 293)
    4 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
    Seeks opinion on authorship of Pericles.
  - Hoppe, Harry Reno, 1906- LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Michigan St Clg, East Lansing, MI, 1944 Mar 21 (Box pe 265)
    1 p.; 22 x 14 cm.
  - Hoppe, Harry Reno, 1906- LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Michigan St Clg, East Lansing, MI, 1946 Aug 24 (Box pe 265)
    1 p.; 23 x 21 cm.
    Asks Greg to forward book to Roy
    Moore, headmaster of a school in
    Rugby.
  - Hoppe, Harry Reno, 1906- LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Brussels, Belgium, 1947 Jan 22 (Box pe 265)
    Thanks for criticism of John of Bordeaux article; will respond
    soon.
  - Howard, Arthur ALS to J. O. T. Howard, Steyning, Sussex, 1956 Jun 7 (Box pe 234)
    Permits W. W. Greg to examine a
    Shakespeare quarto in his private
    collection; seeks to avoid
    publicity.
  - Howard, Arthur ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Steyning, [Sussex], 1956 Jun 16 (Box pe 234)
    Confirms Greg's reading of quarto.
  - Hughes, Robert ALS to Percy Simpson, Penrhyndeudraeth, North Wales, n.y. Sep 10 (Box pe 388)
    2 p.; 12 x 17 cm.
    Presents book; thanks for letter.
  - Huntington, Henry Edwards, 1850-1927 LS to Deighton, Bell and Co., San Marino, CA (Box pe 247)
    No book facsimiles will be made for
    sale now.
  - Huxley, Aldous, 1894-1963 LS to Sir Ernest Benn, Sanary, 1930 Aug 2 (Box pe 430)
    1 p.; 27 x 21 cm.
    Regarding his preface to "Mr. Pink's
    book"; payment expected in books
    from Benn's catalogue.
  - Jerrod, Douglas LS to Percy Simpson, London, 1930 Sep 10 (Box pe 406)
    Thanks for letter; pleased that Simpson
    likes The Masque of Queens recently
    published.
  - Johnson, Reginald Brimley, 1867-1932 ALS to Percy Alfred Scholes, Holland Park, [London], 1930 Mar 30 (Box pe 24)
    4 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
    Discusses ms. sources pertaining to
    the Burney family; lists some "live
    connections," i.e. descendants and
    relatives of the Burneys
  - Johnson, Reginald Brimley, 1867-1932 ALS to Percy Alfred Scholes, Holland Park, [London], 1930 May 5 (Box pe 24)
    Continues discussion of sources for
    research of the Burneys
  - Johnson, Samuel, 1649-1703 ALS to [James Wace], n.p., ca. 1686 (Box pb 84)
    1 p.; 19 x 14 cm.
    Presents sermon [printed; bound in
    this volume]; states opposition to
    "Popish" religion.
  - Jones, H. W. LS to G. N. Clark, Wallasey, Cheshire, 1949 Nov 27 (Box pe 158)
    Suggests that Urban Hjarne did not
    visit England, contrary to Clark's
    assertion.
  - Kellner, Leon, 1859- ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Vienna, 1924 Jan 24 (Box pe 258)
    Thanks for corrections.
  - Kellner, Leon ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Benyamina, Palestine, 1925 Oct 21 (Box pe 258)
    1 p.; 15 x 12.
    Thanks for kind review.
  - King, Charles ALS to [unknown recipient], Oxford, n.y. Sep 12 (Box pe 354)
    Presents book of poems in hope that
    one or more will be published in
    upcoming anthology.
  - King, Edward, 1735?-1807 Note on the text of a new edition of his Remarks on the Signs of the Times, n.d. (Box pc 309)
    2 p.; 13 cm. x 10 cm.
    With biographical notes on King
    "communicated by Mrs. King to
    Mr. Britton, 1810."
    With tipped in page of biographical
    notes on King.
  - Lam, George L. ALS to James M. Osborn, Yale U Library, New Haven, CT, 1952 May 23 (Box pe 150)
    1 p.; 8 x 14 cm.
    Quotes advertisement of Joseph Spence
    from 1746.
  - L'Estrange, Roger, "A Key to Hudibras", ca. 1715 (Box pc 84.v2)
    20 p.; 15 x 10 cm.
    Provides explanations and notes on Hudibras.
    Anon. ms. copy.
  - Lightwood, James Thomas, 1856-1944 ALS to Percy Alfred Scholes, West Beach, Lytham, 1938 Jul 25 (Box pd 26)
    Presents book; discusses disposition
    of music library; tells of life in
    retirement.
  - Little, Andrew George, 1863-1945 ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Risborough, Sevenoaks, 1938 Jun 22 (Box pe 40)
    2 p.; 17 x 13 cm.
    Thanks for writing Latin address.
  - Long, Percy W. LS to Percy Simpson, New York, NY, 1941 Feb 14 (Box pe 394)
    Answers letter; mentions project to
    microfilm mss. in Great Britain.
  - Lyell, James Patrick Richardson, 1871- 1949 ALS to Percy Simpson, Boar's Hill, Oxford, 1935 Feb 1 (Box pe 384)
    Presents book; thanks for help
    anticipates reading Simpson's
  - Macaulay, George Campbell, 1852-1915 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Great Shelford, Cambridge, n.d. (Box pd 188)
    Encloses proof of "Nomine Sacra"
    proposes alternate title,
    "Abbreviation of Sacred Names."
  - Macdonald, Hugh. ALS to unnamed recipient, Caius Clg, Cambridge, n.d. (Box pe 389)
  - McKerrow, Ronald Brunless, 1872-1940 ALS to Percy Simpson, Brook Green, 1914 Jul 6 (Box pe 411)
  - Madon, F. ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Bodleian Library, Oxford, 1907 Nov 23 (Box pe 309)
    Confirms reading of first quarto of The Contention.
  - Mallaby, Howard George Charles, 1902-1978 ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, St. Edward's School, Oxford, n.y. Feb 23 (Box pe 44)
    1 p.; 23 x 17 cm.
    Lists several Wordsworth poems with
    "cdcdee" rhyme; asks if that refutes
    Garrod's claim that Wordworth uses
    it only twice [see Keats, p. 145].
  - Malone, Edmond, 1741-1812 ALS to Thomas Astle, Queen Anne Street, 1802 Jul 10 (Box pc 67)
    3 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
    On dating death of one of fifteen
    William Gascoignes; believes Sir
    William Gascoigne, judge, died 1413-
    1415.
  - Malone, Edmond, 1741-1812 ALS to William Elliot, Holley Place, 1810 Jul 21 (Box pd 86)
    1p.; 18 x 12 cm.
    Presents book; admits errors in
    present edition.
  - Malone, Edmond, 1741-1812 ALS to William Elliot, Holley Place, n.y. Aug 15 (Box pd 86)
    2 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
    Presents new leaf and other
    corrections for Biographical Memoir of the Late Right Honourable William Windham
  - Margoliouth, Herschel Maurice, 1887- ALS to Percy Simpson, Oxford, 1927 Sep 8 (Box pe 379.v1)
  - Martin [first name illegible] ALS to [T. Wright], Southwell, 1833 Apr 23 (Box pd 69)
    Asks for opinion of books' value.
  - Maury, Allen ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, University Clg, London, 1942 Apr 30 (Box pe 226)
    Thanks for letter; comments on recent
    death of R. W. Chambers.
  - Maxwell, J. C. ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, King's College, U of Durham, 1952 Dec 6 (Box pe 272)
    6 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
    Responds to Greg's comments on textual
    problems in Titus Andronicus,
    particularly source for the folio and
    the role of the prompt book.
  - Maxwell, J. C. ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, King's College, U of Durham, 1952 Dec 15 (Box pe 272)
    3 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
    On textual problems, especially with
    the prompt book and quartos.
  - Maxwell, J. C. ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, King's College, U of Durham, 1954 Sep 3 (Box pe 272)
    6 p.; 20 x 18 cm.
    Thanks for review; lengthly response
    to various criticisms, especially
    concerning authorship, dating, and
    bibliography.
  - Mead, Herman R. LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery, San Marino, CA, 1956 May 31 (Box pe 312)
    1 p.; 15 x 23 cm.
    Describes condition of Midsummer Night's Dream and King John in
    the Huntington Library; reports that
    Folger has King John; offers to
    permit reproduction.
  - "Memoir of the Late Joseph Ritson.", ca. 1803 (Box pd 174)
    10 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
    Account, in Edmond Malone's hand, of
    Ritson's life, with a list of his
    publications. [Bound in with a
    catalog from the sale of Ritson's
    library. A note in the volume in
    another hand attributes the memoir
    to an account by William Godwin in
    in the Nov 1803 Monthly Magazine .]
  - Milgate, W. LS to Heathcote William Garrod, Merton Clg, Oxford, 1950 Jun 17 (Box pe 46.v1)
    Concerns meaning and use of "sindon."
  - Millar, E. G. LS to [recipients unknown], British Museum, 1946 Dec 6 (Box pb 97)
    1 p.; 18 x 19 cm.
    Suggests that author of ms. notes in
    the book is John, Second Lord
    Stanhope of Harrington.
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852 ALS to Mr. Power, n.p., [1813] (Box pd 61)
    1 p.; 23 x 20 cm.
    Orders copy of Irish Melodies to be
    sent to Mr. Thompson; discusses
    alterations in "Midnight Moon."
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852 ALS to Mr. Power, n.p., 1814 Jan 8 (Box pd 61)
    Tells of favorable comments in the Edingburgh Review; suspects that
    Lord Byron will dedicate a power to
    him; hopes to go to France and Italy
    to collect music.
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852 ALS to Mr. Power, n.p., 1815 (Box pd 61)
    Sends melody; hopes that Power will
    bring music; Lord Byron has sent
    him a song, but Moore is having
    trouble setting it to music.
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852 ALS to Mr. Power, n.p., [1815] (Box pd 61)
    Thanks for Power's visit to his mother
    discusses placement of songs in
    forthcoming volume; sorting out
    Stevenson's "chaff from his grain."
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852 ALS to Mr. Power, n.p., 1819 Feb 26 (Box pd 61)
    Has found some good melodies.
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852 ALS to Mr. Power, n.p., 1819 Mar 25 (Box pd 61)
    1 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
    Asks him to deny Tom Crib; sends money.
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852 ALS to Mr. Power, n.p., 1820 Jan 27 (Box pd 61)
    Tells of hardship in France
    struggling to finish new work.
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852 ALS to Mr. Power, Champs Elyseés, Paris, 1820 Feb 8 (Box pd 61)
    1 p.; 18 x 20 cm.
    Promises third number by end of June
    tells of work he recently sent.
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852 ALS to Mr. Power, n.p., [1820] Feb 28 (Box pd 61)
    Promises a musical tour.
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852 ALS to Mr. Power, n.p., 1822 Jan 7 (Box pd 61)
    Expresses disapproval of Kinnaird's
    plan; returning to England early for
    fiscal reasons; hopes that Power can
    be counted on to help monetarily.
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852 ALS to Mr. Power, n.p., 1825 Apr 6 (Box pd 61)
    Has much work to do.
  - More, Hannah, 1745-1833 Letter in third person to Thomas Cadell and William Davies, Barley Wood, 1811 Feb 9 (Box pd 249)
    1 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
    Presents book (volume 2).
  - More, Hannah, 1745-1833. Letter in third person to Thomas Cadell and Williams Davies, n.p., 1811 Feb 16 (Box pd 248.v1)
    Requests proof sheets as soon as
    possible, as the printer has
    asked for them.
  - More, Hannah, 1745-1833 Letter in third person to Thomas Cadell and William Davies, Cowslip Green, n.y. Jul 31 (Box pd 249)
    Presents book (vols. 5-6).
  - More, Hannah, 1745-1833 Letter in third person to Thomas Cadell and Williams Davies, Bath (Box pd 248.v1)
    Requests to know amount due her for Strictures; asks when the eight
    volumes will be available.
  - More, Hannah, 1745-1833 ALS to [unknown recipient], Barley Wood, n.d. (Box pd 249)
    3 p.; 19 x 11 cm.
    Satisfied with proofs; requests copies
    for several people; suggests
    advertisement methods. [1.5 pp. in
    a different hand.]
  - Murray, John, 1851-1928 ALS to Walter Begley, Albemarle St., London, 1903 Apr 7 (Box pe 407)
    On exceptions taken by John Clayton
    over allusions in Begley's Is it Shakespeare?.
  - Needham, Francis ALS to James M. Osborn, Worksop, Nottinghamshire, 1937 Jun 6 (Box pe 191)
  - Newman, John Henry, 1801-1890 ALS to Frederick Charles Husenbeth, Birmingham, 1860 Mar 10 (Box pd 156)
    Congratulates Husenbeth on publication
    of Emblems of Saints.
  - Nicholson, F. C. ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Library, The University, Edinburgh, 1934 Aug 1 (Box pe 301)
    Provides reading of Titus Andronicus quarto.
  - Nixon, Howard M. ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, British Museum, London, ca. 1954 (Box pe 211)
    Replies on behalf of F. C. Francis
    gives details on STC 10106; reports
    that STC 10095 is missing.
  - Nixon, Howard M. ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, British Museum, London, 1954 Feb 23 (Box pe 211)
    Suspects that Pollard and Redgrave
    ordered the Injuctions in the STC
    STC 10095 still missing.
  - Nixon, Howard M. ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, British Museum, London, 1954 Apr 20 (Box pe 211)
    Details the versos of several title-
    pages in the STC.
  - Norrington, Arthyr Lionel Pugh, 1899- 1982 LS to Heathcote William Garrod, Trinity College, Oxford, 1956 Mar 26 (Box pe 50)
    Discusses correction to last two
    stanzas of A. H. Clough's poem,
    "Sehnsucht."
  - Norrington, Thomas ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Trinity College, Oxford, 1957 Nov 7 (Box pe 49.v1)
    2 p.; 13 x 20 cm.
    Concerns search for meaning of the
    word "fuosich."
  - Oates, John Claud Trewinard, 1912- ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, University Library, Cambridge, 1955 Oct 14 (Box pe 326)
    Hopes Greg will review a monograph by
    J. K. Walton.
  - Osborn, James M. L to S. W. Woodward, n.p., 1970 Aug 10 (Box pe 187)
    Thanks for gifts; will send photocopies
    of parts of Maurice Johnson's ms.
    hopes to visit.
  - Owen, Charles ALS to Mr. Bartlett, n.p., 1838 Jul 6 (Box pc 85)
    1 p.; 12 x 20 cm.
    Sends copy of Weever's Funeral Monuments and two research notes.
  - Pafford, John Henry Pyle, 1900- ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, U of London, 1953 Nov 19 (Box pe 239.v1)
    Cannot find definition of "vampres"
    gives definitions of "vampers" from
    several sources.
  - Page, P.S. ALS to Augustus Jessop, Norwich, 1907 May 2 (Box pd 156)
    On omissions in Husenbeth's Emblems of Saints; inquires about emblem of
    unnamed bishop and about St. Edmund.
  - Palgrave, Francis Turner, 1824-1897 ALS to Frederick Locker-Lampson, Lyme Regis, Dorset, n.y. Aug 10 (Box pd 81)
    About family.
  - Palgrave, Francis Turner, 1824-1897 ALS to Frederick Locker-Lampson, Chester Terrace, 1879 Jun 27 (Box pd 81)
    Thanks for permitting to read sonnets
    compliments them; discusses upcoming
    estate sales.
  - Pardoe, Elizabeth ALS to Henry Colburn, Bradenham Lodge, 1837 Oct 3 (Box pd 141)
    2 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
    Sends corrected sheets for "The City
    of the Sultan"; vol. 2 will follow.
  - Parrott, Thomas Marc, 1866-1960 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, U of Colorado, Boulder, CO, 1937 Jan 27 (Box pe 235)
    2 p.; 28 x 22 cm.
    Concerns Shakespeare's dedication to
    "All Fools"; discusses authenticity
    of certain Forman entries.
  - Parsons, J. Denham ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Chiswick, [London], 1935 Jul 20 (Box pe 316)
    Discusses variant spelling of
    Shakespeare as "Shakspere"; objects
    to Greg's reading of Arber.
  - Parsons, J. Denham ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Chiswick, [London], 1935 Jul 24 (Box pe 316)
    Wishes to avoid controversy; restates
    objections; asks for lengthier reply.
  - Parsons, J. Denham ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Chiswick, [London], 1935 Jul 31 (Box pe 316)
    Continues discussion of problems in
    Shakespearian authorship.
  - Pollard, Alfred William, 1859-1944 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, British Museum, London, 1921 Jan 7 (Box pe 242)
    Urges Greg to order Huntington's
    facsimiles; summarizes response to
    Seymour De Ricci's introduction to Fulgens and Lucres.
  - Pollard, Alfred William, 1859-1944 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Wimbledon, n.y., Sunday (Box pe 262)
    3 p.; 11 x 18 cm.
    Discusses suicide of colleague; on
    textual problems in King Lear.
  - Pratt, Dana J. LS to William K. Wimsatt, Yale U Press, New Haven, CT, 1972 Oct 2 (Box pe 429)
    Appreciates recent chess talk; encloses Science article about alleged
    attempt of Fischer to electronically
    sabotage Spassky.
  - Prior, Matthew, 1664-1721 ALS to Richardson Pack, Westminster, 1719 May 4 (Box fpc 33)
    Presentation inscription.
  - Richmond, Sir Bruce Lyttelton, 1871-1964 ALS to George Stuart Gordon, Sumner Pl, [1937] (Box pe 367)
    Sending poems of Ronald Gorell Barnes,
    3rd baron Gorell, for review.
  - Ribeiro, Alvaro F. V., 1947- L to The Examiner, Oxford, Balliol Clg, Oxford, 1980 Jul 31 (Box fpe 13)
    2 p.; 30 x 21 cm. [photostatic copy]
    Suggests which portions of his thesis
    [An Edition of the Letters of Dr.
    Charles Burney] may be read by those
    who do not wish to read it in its
    entirety.
  - Robins, George Henry, 1778-1847 "Correspondence between Mr. Robins and Mr. [W.W.] Simpson": anon. MS copies of letters dated 1841-1842., [ca. 1842] (Box pd 58)
    32 p.; 22 x 15 cm.
    The letters concern a dispute over
    methods of auctioneering. Bound with
    a printed pamphlet concerning sale
    of the Ribston Hall estate.
  - Robinson, Charles J. ALS to John Ruskin, Stoke Newington, [London], 1906 May 21 (Box pd 164)
    Offers some corrections to book.
  - Rothenstein, Sir William, 1872-1945 ALS to Mr. Gollancz, n.d. (Box pe 430)
    Concerns the use and copyright of his
  - Rowley, C. E. ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Holywell, Oxford, 1957 Oct 30 (Box pe 49.v1)
    Concerns picture of Arthur Hugh Clough.
  - Ruffhead, Owen, 1723-1769 ALS to George Thicknesse; Cursitor's Street, Chancery Lane, 1769 Feb 11 (Box pc 292)
    2 p; 19 cm. x 24 cm.
    Presenting this copy of his The Life of Alexander Pope.
    Annotated by Thicknesse with
    biographical information on Ruffhead.
    Inlaid page margin annotated, "J.
    Turner 1801."
    Acc.: 03.1.4
  - Rutherston, Albert Daniel, 1881-1953 ALS to Robertson, Cadogan Square, [London], 1927 Sep 26 (Box pe 430)
    Encourages Robertson's work.
  - S-----, J. ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, All Souls Clg, Oxford, 1950 Jun 10 (Box pe 46.v1)
    On the meaning of "sindon" in Donne's Pseudo-martyr.
  - Sam [last name unknown] ALS to Frank Percy and Joanne Wilson, Venice, Italy, 1960 Aug 31 (Box pe 348)
    Greetings from vacation.
  - Savoy, Gundred H. ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Shirley, Croydon, 1945 Jun 21 (Box pe 52)
    6 p.; 18 x 14 cm.
    Raises two points about A. E. Housman's
    poetry missed by Garrod in a recent
  - Scholes, Percy Alfred, 1877-1958 L to Lawrence Haward, n.p., 1942 Feb 20 (Box fpe 3)
    2 p.; 23 x 18 cm. [typed copy]
    Opines that the portrait of Charles
    Burney could be authentic, and gives
    additional supporting information.
  - Scholes, Percy Alfred, 1877-1958 L to Lawrence Haward, n.p., 1942 Mar 21 (Box fpe 3)
    2 p.; 25 x 20 cm. [typed copy]
    Has no record of Charles Burney
    junior painted as a youth; during
    the period in question, Burney was
    in Scotland, in disgrace.
  - Scholes, Percy Alfred, 1877-1958 L to Reginald Brimley Johnson, n.p., 1930 Apr 30 (Box pe 24)
    Discusses the Burney family's
    involvement with music and problems
    of research.
  - Scholes, Percy Alfred,, 1877-1958 L to Reginald Brimley Johnson, n.p., 1930 May 14 (Box pe 24)
    Continued discussion of research
    sources on Burneys, including a
    painting of Bardy hanging in the
    Society of Arts in London.
  - Simpson, Andrew ALS to [Walter Wilson Greg], Salisbury (Box pe 268)
    1 p.; 13 x 17 cm.
    Agrees with opinion on handwriting
    of Falstaff.
  - Simpson, Percy, 1865-1962 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Highfield, Oxford, 1937 Mar 29 (Box pe 336)
    Thanks for and comments on review.
  - Sisam, Kenneth LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Oxford, 1941 Aug 22 (Box pe 219)
    1 p.; 16 x 20 cm.
  - Sisam, Kenneth ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, St. Mary's, Isles of Scilly, 1958 Dec 20 (Box pe 230)
    2 p.; 20 x 13
    Describes life in the remote village he
    inhabits; explains that lack of books
    and inability to travel cause his
    withdrawal from academic life.
  - Sissen, G., University Clg, London ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, 1943 Nov 1 (Box pe 244)
    Asks about printing methods and
    prices prior to 1654.
  - Smith, Dane Farnsworth ALS to Montague Summers, U of New Mexico, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1937 Jul 28 (Box pe 168)
    4 p.; 23 x 15 cm.
    Apologizes for disagreement; thanks
    for letter.
  - Smith, David Nichol, 1875-1962 ALS to Albert Bernard Burney, Oxford, 1946 Jun 25 (Box fpe 8)
    Presents book; thanks for kindness.
  - Smith, George Charles Moore, 1858-1946 ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Sheffield, 1923 Nov 21 (Box pe 36)
    4 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
    Thanks for notes on Lord Herbert's
    Latin poems; includes additional
    comments on many of the poems.
  - Smith, George Charles Moore, 1858-1946 ALS to Heathcote William Garrod, Sheffield, 1923 Nov 22 (Box pe 36)
    Agrees that "Euryale" in Herbert's
    poem is the dying Gorgon.
  - Smith, George Charles Moore, 1858-1946 ALS to Percy Simpson, Sheffield, 1918 Sep 27 (Box pd 208)
    Agrees that Lord Herbert's verse
    antedates Master's verse.
  - Smith, Robert Metcalf, 1886-1952 ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Lehigh U, Bethlehem, PA, 1928 Mar 7 (Box pe 250)
    1 p.; 28 x 18 cm.
    Reports that his pamphlet will be
    part of second folio section
    of STC; hopes that Greg will
    proofread before it goes to press
    considers explanation of title leaf
    having been set up three times.
  - Smithson, Edward Walter ALS to Walter Begley, Hitchin, 1903 Dec 12 (Box pe 407)
    Congratulates Begley on his book Is it Shakespeare; hopes to meet him.
  - Smollett, Tobias George, 1721-1771 (Box pc 310/2)
    The History and Adventures of the Renowned Don Quixote.... (London: 1765)
    Copy of the first edition marked up
    as printer's copy, with some ms.
    changes and annotations, possibly
    in Smollett's hand.
  - Southam, T. W. ALS to [C. E. Manwaring], Valetta, Malta, n.y. Jun 20 (Box pe 23)
    Sends information about an incident in
    Burney's life from William Hickey's
    diary. [includes typed page
    detailing incident; 25 x 20 cm.]
  - Spencer, Hazelton, 1893-1944 LS to Walter Wilson Greg, Johns Hopkins U, Baltimore, MD, 1940 Jan 30 (Box pe 252)
    Presents book; thanks for contribution
    of review; gives good wishes "in
    these dreadful times"; opines that US
    will stay out of war.
  - Squire, John Collings, 1884-1958 ALS to Percy Simpson, Strand, London, 1926 (Box pe 403)
    Apologizes for late reply and failure
    to acknowledge Simpson's pamphlet.
  - Stamp, Alfred Edward, 1870- ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Public Records Office, [London], 1929 Jun 17 (Box fpe 12)
    4 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
    Reports that--according to the
    Government Laboratory--the paper was
    new when the work in question was
    written.
  - Stamp, Alfred Edward, 1870- ALS to Walter Wilson Greg, Public Records Office, [London], 1930 Nov 17 (Box fpe 12)
    1 p.; 19 x 12 cm.
    Thanks for copy of "The Great Work."
  - Stead, William Force, 1884- ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Trinity Clg, Washington, DC, [1958] (Box pe 364)
  - Stead, William Force, 1884- ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Finstock, Oxfordshire, 1928 Jan 14 (Box pe 363)
    Thanks for letter; comments on
    Pitt-River. [Appended note by
    Edmund Blunden concerns Clare's Village Minstrel .]
  - Stead, William Force, 1884- ALS to C. H. Wilkinson, Worcester Clg, Oxford, n.d. (Box pe 363)
  - Stock, Elliot ALS to Walter Begley, Paternoster Row, London, 1903 Mar 30 (Box pe 407)
    On the printing of several of Begley's
    works. With excerpts from Andrew
    Lang in Longman's magazine.